<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>For more details...</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/more/</guid>
      <description>For detailed information about my professional experience and education, please refer to my LinkedIn profile or drop me a line!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some tech</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/tech/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some of the tech I&amp;rsquo;ve crossed path with since the beginning of times&amp;hellip; Just some examples, I&amp;rsquo;m an easy-learner and flexible person, so I try to adapt to use whatever is needed or best for the task. Being open-minded in tech is a must! 
Full stack (and web development)        
Other programming languages  
Also VGDL, LISP, Prolog and VBA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences organisation</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/conferences/</guid>
      <description>2019 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG) August 2019, London, UK
Webmaster
 IGGI Conference September 2018, London, UK
Workshop chair</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/talks/</guid>
      <description>IGGI Conference September 2018, London, UK
“Using a Team of General AI Algorithms to Assist Game Design and Testing”
Slides
 IEEE Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG) August 2018, Maastricht, Netherlands
Presentation of &amp;ldquo;Using a Team of General AI Algorithms to Assist Game Design and Testing&amp;rdquo; paper, Session: Vision Papers
Slides
 IGGI Conference September 2017, York, UK
“The General Video Game Playing Challenge: Improving RHEA &amp;amp; Playing Beyond Win”, with Raluca D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/publications/</guid>
      <description>2018 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Simon M Lucas and Diego Perez-Liebana, &amp;ldquo;Using a Team of General AI Algorithms to Assist Game Design and Testing&amp;rdquo;, Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG). IEEE, 2018
 2017 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Annie Louis and Diego Perez-Liebana, &amp;ldquo;Beyond Playing to Win: Diversifying Heuristics for GVGAI&amp;rdquo;, Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG). IEEE, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online form</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/qmrec1968_form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/qmrec1968_form/</guid>
      <description>If having the interview in person is not an option for you, I have set up an online form with a series of questions related with game testing and the procedures carried out in your company, both when using human playtesters and automatic testing.
Please, consider filling the form if you have some time as it could be very helpful to set up my experiments and to shape my research. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to send me an email to c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/projects/</guid>
      <description>Some code that can be shared with the world 
 kisenshi.github.io I use something called Hugo, which is a fantastic static website engine that allows me to have 100% control of the site; precisely what I was looking for. This repository contains the static code once it has been generated to be published. Basically, it’s the site you are visiting at the moment! 
 Portal 2D Game developed using the GVGAI framework (forked into my repository) as assessment for the Game AI Module took at Goldsmiths University in February 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biography - Cristina Guerrero-Romero</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/summary/</guid>
      <description>What I do I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student at Queen Mary University of London. 
What I&amp;rsquo;ve done I studied Computer and Software Engineering at Universidad Autonoma de Madrid (Spain), moved to London and worked as a web developer (in different languages) for a couple of years. I decided to make a change in my career and opted for the Artificial Intelligence and games world, which I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews in person</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/qmrec1968_person/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/qmrec1968_person/</guid>
      <description>I am based in London, and I do travel frequently to Brighton, so if your company is based in one of these two locations (or close by), we could meet for a quick chat, giving me the chance to ask follow up questions and to clarify details that might come up from the answers.
To schedule an interview, or if you have any further questions, do not hesitate to send me an email to c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2018 - Pass my Pants (aka Pants Mission)</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2018_01_29_global_game_jam_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2018_01_29_global_game_jam_2018/</guid>
      <description>The Global Game Jam (GGJ) is an annual game creation event taking place worldwide in different physical locations. Jammers have 48 hours to make a game based on a certain theme. This year it was transmission.
Last year I used Unity to develop a poetry puzzle platformer and, even when it was pretty chilled because my team took the decision to enjoy the experience, I had in mind doing something different this time; preferably avoiding the pain of setting up complicated environments and tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEN Entrepreneurship Workshop 2017</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_09_19_entrepreneurship_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 19:27:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_09_19_entrepreneurship_workshop/</guid>
      <description>On 19-20th September 2017, the Digital Economy Network (DEN), in collaboration with Digital Catapult, organised a two-days entrepreneurship workshop for EPSRC Digital Economy PhD students. As part of IGGI, I had the chance to attend.
On Tuesday I went to the Digital Catapult&amp;rsquo;s offices (where they have amazing views of St. Pancras!) with the idea of learning as much as possible from those two days, and I certainly did!
Philip Treleaven, professor at UCL, gave a series of lessons in entrepreneurship, including how to identify the idea, branding and vision, suggestions for the pitch and funding sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Techmakers Summit 2017</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_03_23_wtm2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_03_23_wtm2017/</guid>
      <description>On 22nd of March 2017, I went to the super cool new Google offices in St Pancras Square to attend the annual Google&amp;rsquo;s International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day Summit organised by WomenTechmakers and, once again, I felt really inspired and lucky to belong to the amazing tech community.
The agenda looked really interesting so I was really looking forward to it. The registration opened up almost an hour before Sarah Drinkwater kicked off the event, which gave enough time to eat some cheese and delicious cupcakes and meet some of the other amazing attendees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game AI Module Project - Portal 2D</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_02_27_game_ai_module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_02_27_game_ai_module/</guid>
      <description>As part of the Game AI module I took at Goldsmiths University on February 2017 it was needed to design, implement and playtest an AI-based game. There was no technichal constraints or limitations. The idea was making something that could be useful later for my research and, as I need to use the GVGAI Framework, I opted to use it in order to get familiar with it. Valve&amp;rsquo;s Portal series are in the top of my favourite games list (check them out if you haven&amp;rsquo;t), so I decided to make my game based on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2017 - Her Resonance</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_01_23_global_game_jam_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_01_23_global_game_jam_2017/</guid>
      <description>The Global Game Jam (GGJ) is an annual game creation event taking place worldwide in different physical locations. At certain time, a theme is announced and jammers have 48 hours to make a game based on it. Thousands of people participate all around the world, creating thousands of games (more than 7000 games have been created in the 2017 edition) and the number increases every year.
IGGI signs up every year as one of the GGJ local sites, taking place in one of the collaborating institutions so, as part of the programme, I spent the weekend in York making a game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Development Module Project - Hungry Penguins Game</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2016_11_11_game_development_module/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2016_11_11_game_development_module/</guid>
      <description>At the IGGI Game Development Module I took at Goldsmiths University in November 2016, it was needed to develop a game using Unity. I teamed up with one of the other students of the programme, Rory Davidson, and we created a puzzle-platformer.
Game The idea of the game came up during the brainstorming session we had at the beginning of the module. We wanted to develop a game featuring penguins living in a city, being forced to steal fish in order to eat and survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello IGGI!</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2016_09_04_hello_iggi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2016_09_04_hello_iggi/</guid>
      <description>I am really excited to finally say Hello IGGI as I am one of the new students in the University of Essex! It is a great opportunity and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what comes out of the next 4 years!
But wait&amp;hellip; What is IGGI??  Right! I&amp;rsquo;ll explain!
The Intelligent Games and Game Intelligence (IGGI) PhD programme is the biggest fully funded research programme in Artificial Intelligence and Games in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Hackathon</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2015_03_11_my_first_hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 15:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2015_03_11_my_first_hackathon/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently realised how big the tech community is here in London (I was completely blind before) and the amount of interesting events, meetups and workshops that can be found almost daily around the city. Last weekend I decided to attend to my first Hackathon and, although on Sunday I was completely exhausted, it was such a great experience!
The hackathon was organised by Talented Heads and hosted by Makers Academy to celebrate the International Women&amp;rsquo;s day, encourage diversity in tech and inspire more women to join this amazing industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2015_03_10_hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 23:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2015_03_10_hello_world/</guid>
      <description>The first post has to be this one!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little bit about me</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! I’m Cris; a Spaniard in love with London, where I’ve been living since 2013. Although I had always enjoyed creative tasks like drawing and painting; I opted for a more technical career, and I absolutely love it! I am passionate about solving problems, coding and the feel when something you have built actually works!
I worked as a web developer for a couple of years before I decided to make a change to the exciting world of AI and games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/publications/</guid>
      <description>2018 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Simon M Lucas and Diego Perez-Liebana, &amp;ldquo;Using a Team of General AI Algorithms to Assist Game Design and Testing&amp;rdquo;, Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG). IEEE, 2018
 2017 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Annie Louis and Diego Perez-Liebana, &amp;ldquo;Beyond Playing to Win: Diversifying Heuristics for GVGAI&amp;rdquo;, Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG). IEEE, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>