<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact me</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to drop me a line to c.guerreroromero[at]qmul.ac.uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo: Diversifying Heuristics for GVGAI</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/demos/</guid>
      <description>This demo shows the different behaviours of a general agent (Random Search) when using four different heuristics (goals): Winning Maximization (WMH), Exploration Maximization (EMH), Knowledge Discovery (KDH) and Knowledge Estimation (KEH).  The game is one of the games provided in the GVGAI framework, Butterflies. To win the game, all the butterflies must be captured before the time runs out or before all the cocoons are opened. Catching butterflies increases the score +2, so the more butterflies captured, higher the final score is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/publications/</guid>
      <description>2021 Cristina Guerrero-Romero and Diego Perez-Liebana. &amp;ldquo;MAP-Elites to Generate a Team of Agents that Elicits Diverse Automated Gameplay&amp;rdquo;, Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG), 2021.
 
Related demo
 Diego Perez-Liebana, Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Alexander Dockhorn, Dominik Jeurissen and Linjie Xu. &amp;ldquo;Generating Diverse and Competitive Play-Styles for Strategy Games&amp;rdquo;. Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG), 2021.
 2020 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Shringi Kumari, Diego Perez-Liebana and Sebastian Deterding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>