<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact me</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to drop me a line to c.guerreroromero[at]qmul.ac.uk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo: Diversifying Heuristics for GVGAI</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/demos/</guid>
      <description>This demo shows the different behaviours of a general agent (Random Search) when using four different heuristics (goals): Winning Maximization (WMH), Exploration Maximization (EMH), Knowledge Discovery (KDH) and Knowledge Estimation (KEH).  The game is one of the games provided in the GVGAI framework, Butterflies. To win the game, all the butterflies must be captured before the time runs out or before all the cocoons are opened. Catching butterflies increases the score +2, so the more butterflies captured, higher the final score is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/research/publications/</guid>
      <description>2019 Damien Anderson, Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Diego Perez-Liebana, Philip Rodgers and John Levine, &amp;ldquo;Ensemble Decision Systems for General Video Game Playing&amp;rdquo;, Conference on Games (CoG). IEEE, 2019

 2018 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Simon M Lucas and Diego Perez-Liebana, &amp;ldquo;Using a Team of General AI Algorithms to Assist Game Design and Testing&amp;rdquo;, Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG). IEEE, 2018
 2017 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Annie Louis and Diego Perez-Liebana, &amp;ldquo;Beyond Playing to Win: Diversifying Heuristics for GVGAI&amp;rdquo;, Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>