<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/tags/women_in_tech/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/tags/women_in_tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Techmakers Summit 2017</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_03_23_WTM2017_Google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_03_23_WTM2017_Google/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 22nd of March 2017, I went to the super cool new &lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt; offices in St Pancras Square to attend the annual &lt;em&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day Summit&lt;/em&gt; organised by &lt;em&gt;WomenTechmakers&lt;/em&gt; and, once again, I felt really inspired and lucky to belong to the amazing tech community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agenda looked really interesting so I was really looking forward to it. The registration opened up almost an hour before &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sarahdrinkwater&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sarah Drinkwater&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; kicked off the event, which gave enough time to eat some cheese and delicious cupcakes and meet some of the other amazing attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive post_img_right&#34; src=&#34;http://kisenshi.github.io/img/posts/women_techmakers_2017/jessica_hummel_talk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Welcome to the technology circus&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening remarks with the title &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone is welcome here&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, by &lt;strong&gt;Suzanne Timmons&lt;/strong&gt; (Operations Director at &lt;em&gt;Googler Engagement&lt;/em&gt;) focused on diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were followed by the keynote &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Welcome to the technology circus&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Jessica Hummel&lt;/strong&gt;, Software Engineer at &lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt;. She started saying that &amp;ldquo;circus is to the body as tech to the mind&amp;rdquo; and her talk focused on comparing technology with different performing arts in order to give a series of tips to success. She talked about theatre, dance, juggling, acrobatics and mentioned how it is important to recover from injuries and to enjoy the &amp;ldquo;creation of the show&amp;rdquo;. The tips taken from each of the arts are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From theatre -&amp;gt; interaction. It is importanto to interact with other people and be open to their ideas, as having different views can help to achieve great things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From dance -&amp;gt; priorization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From juggling -&amp;gt; simplicity and focus. Starting simple, focusing in quality instead of quantity and increasing difficulty once the smaller tasks are achieved; always having in mind the big picture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From acrobatics -&amp;gt; learn and achieve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary &lt;strong&gt;interact&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;prioritize&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;simplify&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;learn &amp;amp; achieve&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;recover&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;enjoy&lt;/strong&gt; to be successfull. And these tips could be applied to other aspects of life apart from arts or technology. It was a really inspiring talk; probably one of the most inspiring talks I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive post_img_left&#34; src=&#34;http://kisenshi.github.io/img/posts/women_techmakers_2017/rebecca_fiebrink_talk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Machine Learning as Creative Interaction Design Tool&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doc.gold.ac.uk/~mas01rf/Rebecca_Fiebrink_Goldsmiths/welcome.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Rebecca Fiebrink&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Lecturer at &lt;em&gt;Goldsmiths University&lt;/em&gt;, talked about the use of &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Machine Learning as a creative interaction design tool&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, explaining the possibilty of using data for different creative purposes. She made a demo of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wekinator.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wekinator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an open source tool developed by her. It is capable of learning (very fast!) different interactions with the human through the webcam (or any other interactive device) allowing a very quick prototyping and refinement without the need of using code. Its applications are wide (from creating proffesional music and building instruments, to a face expression-meme mapping), giving artists the chance of taking advantage of the technology to express their creativity without the need of having programming-skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a break, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/coderinheels&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gen Ashley&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Sprinzette&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicki Sprinz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Reem Al Seed&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Svetlana Gulijajeva&lt;/strong&gt; joined Sarah for an inspirational Panel. They talked about different topics: programs promoting diversity, mentorship, (good/bad) advices and culture in the workplace. They mentioned that a good culture is based on respect and if a company is not offering what you think it is a right culture for you, it is because you are not in th right place. Based on my experience, I couldn´t agree more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive post_img_center&#34; src=&#34;http://kisenshi.github.io/img/posts/women_techmakers_2017/panel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Panel&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closing talk &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Research and the Next Billion Users&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; was given by &lt;strong&gt;Jeannie Foulsham&lt;/strong&gt;, Senior UX researcher at &lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt;. It was focused on the challenge of creating and developing products for emerging markets like India. It is not only needed to take into consideration the technological development constraints like devices and connectivity issues, but also the cultural differences including languages, inputs and diversity challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a brilliant evening and it is definitely one of the events of the year that it worth attending; will you join me next time?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Hackathon</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2015_03_11_my_first_hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 15:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2015_03_11_my_first_hackathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently realised how big the tech community is here in London (I was completely blind before) and the amount of interesting events, meetups and workshops that can be found almost daily around the city. Last weekend I decided to attend to my first Hackathon and, although on Sunday I was completely exhausted, it was such a great experience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon was organised by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.talentedheads.com/2015/02/10/female-hackathon-planned-london-celebrate-international-womens-day/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talented Heads&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makersacademy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to celebrate the International Women&amp;rsquo;s day, encourage diversity in tech and inspire more women to join this amazing industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived at Makers Academy (really cool) offices on Saturday morning, all I knew was that we would build a project based on the theme &lt;em&gt;Make it Happen - Diversity in Tech&lt;/em&gt; and I needed to bring my laptop, curiosity and imagination; so I could not imagine what all we were there were about to achieve!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&#34; lang=&#34;en-gb&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are the women who will &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakeItHappen?src=hash&#34;&gt;#MakeItHappen&lt;/a&gt; in tech in the future. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/iwdhackathon?src=hash&#34;&gt;#iwdhackathon&lt;/a&gt; you go girls x &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/SBgSLWslvx&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/SBgSLWslvx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Talented Heads (@TalentedHeads) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TalentedHeads/status/574161010057211906&#34;&gt;March 7, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After introducing ourselves and some talking, we were divided into groups to come up with an idea to solve one of the problems we had isolated during the brainstorming. The interesting thing at this point is that, unlike other Hackathons, where the team meanly consists of technical profiles, our teams were formed by women with different skills. This approach provided us various points of view and encouraged us to collaborate to be able to achieve our goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;post_img_right img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;http://kisenshi.github.io/img/posts/my_first_hackathon/cyoa_team.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CYOA team&#34;&gt;
My team was formed by two &lt;strong&gt;designers&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lowndesjo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JessicaLeach6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jess&lt;/a&gt;), two &lt;strong&gt;marketers&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SuzeShardlow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Suze&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alessia_camera&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Alessia&lt;/a&gt;) and two &lt;strong&gt;developers&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/binaryberry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tatiana&lt;/a&gt; and myself). I have to admit that we were very lucky as, without knowing each other at all, it turned out that we had different skills that complemented perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to focus on &lt;strong&gt;childhood&lt;/strong&gt;. We thought that the problem starts during this period, as there are lot of stereotypes and biases surrounding boys&amp;rsquo; and girls&amp;rsquo; daily environment that may affect the way they decide to live their life, and the decisions they take in the future. In general, girls use to get frustrated and give up easily when there is a problem, and the society doesn&amp;rsquo;t encourage them to keep trying and to not be afraid of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lot of deliberation, we came up with an idea we all loved: develop an &lt;strong&gt;educational story-telling platform&lt;/strong&gt; to teach the basic principles of coding and problem solving through interactive exercises. Children would access the platform and create stories based in their favourite fairy tales. Depending on their actions and answers, &lt;strong&gt;the story would change&lt;/strong&gt; (or even conclude) and the more they would progress in the story following &amp;ldquo;the correct path&amp;rdquo;, the more they would be rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the idea was clear, it was time to start working and transform it in a real product to be shown the next day. It was needed a deep analysis, a marketing strategy, a research to find out possible competitors, a working prototype (oriented to the proper target), cute designs for the children&amp;hellip; and a bear, the bear was important! And we had just 24 hours to make it happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&#34; lang=&#34;en-gb&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are back with lots of smiles! Brainstorming whilst having breakfast. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/IWD2015?src=hash&#34;&gt;#IWD2015&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/IWDHackathon?src=hash&#34;&gt;#IWDHackathon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/makingithappen?src=hash&#34;&gt;#makingithappen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/4MISeaEjlw&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/4MISeaEjlw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daria Taylor (@daria_taylor) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/daria_taylor/status/574513998701395968&#34;&gt;March 8, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the technical part, we opted for using Ruby (with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. I had never used Ruby before so I needed to set up the environment and Tatiana spent some time explaining me the basics of Ruby and how Sinatra was structured. It took us some time to be able to actually start working in the product, but we managed quite well and I am very happy with what we were able to produce.
Collaborating, talking, sharing different opinions and ideas (and eating all the delicious food, juices and coffee provided by the lovely organizers) all my team was able to achieve a surprising good quality work in such a short period of time; &lt;a href=&#34;https://code-your-own-adventure.herokuapp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Your Own Adventure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was born and it was ready to be shown to the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;text-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://code-your-own-adventure.herokuapp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://kisenshi.github.io/img/posts/my_first_hackathon/cyoa_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;CYOA logo&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pitching time! The moment to present the product we had been working on during the weekend had arrived, and everyone was tired, but really excited. The other two teams presented some really good ideas as well. One of them was &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/techmentr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TechMentr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a platform to match mentors and mentees in tech; and &lt;strong&gt;Co(de)Create&lt;/strong&gt;, an e-learning platform oriented to support small projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To judge the projects, there was a jury conformed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/coderinheels&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gen Ashley&lt;/a&gt;, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Women-Who-Code-London/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Women Who Code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mseckington&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Melinda&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;FutureLearn&lt;/em&gt; and Clarice from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codefirstgirls.org.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Codefirst:Girls&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. After much deliberation, they announced &lt;strong&gt;Code Your Own Adventure&lt;/strong&gt; as the winning idea!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&#34; lang=&#34;en-gb&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/IWDHackathon?src=hash&#34;&gt;#IWDHackathon&lt;/a&gt; teams also talked about marketing for (not just the tech aspect of) the ideas/products they developed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/91tUiEBe2X&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/91tUiEBe2X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gen A (@coderinheels) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/coderinheels/status/574592772071624704&#34;&gt;March 8, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazing, &lt;strong&gt;our team had won&lt;/strong&gt;!!!! We were so happy and could not believe it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we started working on it, I knew it was a great idea, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to win. To be honest, I was having such a good time during the whole weekend and the environment was so friendly that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the feeling to be in &amp;ldquo;a competition&amp;rdquo;, but we were; and there were &lt;strong&gt;prizes&lt;/strong&gt;!!! We are going to receive a £75 amazon voucher, isn&amp;rsquo;t that great??! My earphones broke last week (and I cannot live without music), so I have quite clear what I am going to spend it on! I include Jess&amp;rsquo; tweet below with a photo of us with the jury so you can see by yourself how happy we were!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&#34; lang=&#34;en-gb&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code Your Own Adventure! Winning team at IWD hackathon &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SuzeShardlow&#34;&gt;@SuzeShardlow&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/binaryberry&#34;&gt;@binaryberry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lowndesjo&#34;&gt;@lowndesjo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CamTechWomen&#34;&gt;@CamTechWomen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/5KuODwN28v&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/5KuODwN28v&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jessica Leach (@JessicaLeach6) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JessicaLeach6/status/574665613551013889&#34;&gt;March 8, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, it was a &lt;strong&gt;great experience&lt;/strong&gt;, I met &lt;strong&gt;amazing women&lt;/strong&gt; passionate about &lt;strong&gt;tech&lt;/strong&gt;, I had fun and learnt a lot. Although on Sunday afternoon I was exhausted (both mentally and physically), it worth it and I would do it again! I have the feeling that I will be seen participating in many other Hackathons in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks the rest of attendees, the jury and the organizers for the amazing pics. It was possible and&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&#34;text-center&#34;&gt;WE MADE IT HAPPEN!&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>