<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>For more details...</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/more/</guid>
      <description>For detailed information about my professional experience and education, please refer to my LinkedIn profile or drop me a line!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some tech</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/tech/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some of the tech I&amp;rsquo;ve crossed path with since the beginning of times&amp;hellip; Just some examples, I&amp;rsquo;m an easy-learner and flexible person, so I try to adapt to use whatever is needed or best for the task. Being open-minded in tech is a must! 
Full stack (and web development)        
Other programming languages  
Also VGDL, LISP, Prolog and VBA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences organisation</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/conferences/</guid>
      <description>2019 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG) August 2019, London, UK
Webmaster
 IGGI Conference September 2018, London, UK
Workshop chair</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/talks/</guid>
      <description>IGGI Conference September 2017, York, UK
“The General Video Game Playing Challenge: Improving RHEA &amp;amp; Playing Beyond Win”, with Raluca D. Gaina.
 IEEE Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG) August 2017, New York, USA
Presentation of &amp;ldquo;Beyond Playing to Win: Diversifying Heuristics for GVGAI&amp;rdquo; paper, Special Session on General Video Game AI
Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/publications/</guid>
      <description>2018 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Simon M Lucas and Diego Perez-Liebana, &amp;ldquo;Using a Team of General AI Algorithms to Assist Game Design and Testing&amp;rdquo;, Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG). IEEE, 2018. To appear.
 2017 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Simon M Lucas and Diego Perez-Liebana, &amp;ldquo;Beyond Playing to Win: Diversifying Heuristics for GVGAI&amp;rdquo;, Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG). IEEE, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/projects/</guid>
      <description>Some code that can be shared with the world 
 kisenshi.github.io I use something called Hugo, which is a fantastic static website engine that allows me to have 100% control of the site; precisely what I was looking for. This repository contains the static code once it has been generated to be published. Basically, it’s the site you are visiting at the moment! 
 Portal 2D Game developed using the GVGAI framework (forked into my repository) as assessment for the Game AI Module took at Goldsmiths University in February 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biography - Cristina Guerrero-Romero</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/summary/</guid>
      <description>What I do I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student at Queen Mary University of London. 
What I&amp;rsquo;ve done I studied Computer and Software Engineering at Universidad Autonoma de Madrid (Spain), moved to London and worked as a web developer (in different languages) for a couple of years. I decided to make a change in my career and opted for the Artificial Intelligence and games world, which I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>