<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>For more details...</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/more/</guid>
      <description>For detailed information about my professional experience and education, please refer to my LinkedIn profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences organisation</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/conferences/</guid>
      <description>2019 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG) August 2019, London, UK
Webmaster
 IGGI Conference September 2018, London, UK
Workshop chair</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/talks/</guid>
      <description>IGGI Conference September 2018, London, UK
“Using a Team of General AI Algorithms to Assist Game Design and Testing”
Slides
 IEEE Computational Intelligence and Games (CIG) August 2018, Maastricht, Netherlands
Presentation of &amp;ldquo;Using a Team of General AI Algorithms to Assist Game Design and Testing&amp;rdquo; paper, Session: Vision Papers
Slides
 IGGI Conference September 2017, York, UK
“The General Video Game Playing Challenge: Improving RHEA &amp;amp; Playing Beyond Win”, with Raluca D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/projects/</guid>
      <description>Some of my code - excludes ongoing work, which I have in a private repository until it is mature enough to be shared with the world! 
 kisenshi.github.io I use something called Hugo, which is a fantastic static website engine that allows me to have 100% control of the site; precisely what I was looking for. This repository contains the static code once it has been generated to be published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/publications/</guid>
      <description>2021 Cristina Guerrero-Romero and Diego Perez-Liebana. &amp;ldquo;MAP-Elites to Generate a Team of Agents that Elicits Diverse Automated Gameplay&amp;rdquo;, Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG), 2021.
 
Related demo
 Diego Perez-Liebana, Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Alexander Dockhorn, Dominik Jeurissen and Linjie Xu. &amp;ldquo;Generating Diverse and Competitive Play-Styles for Strategy Games&amp;rdquo;. Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG), 2021.
 2020 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Shringi Kumari, Diego Perez-Liebana and Sebastian Deterding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biography</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/portfolio/summary/</guid>
      <description>What I do I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student at Queen Mary University of London. I did the first year of my PhD at University of Essex. 
What I&amp;rsquo;ve done I studied Software and Computer Engineering at Universidad Autonoma de Madrid (Spain), moved to London and worked as a web developer (in different languages) for a couple of years. I decided to make a change in my career and started the PhD in AI and games.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>