<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iggi on Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/categories/iggi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iggi on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/categories/iggi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Game AI Module Project - Portal 2D</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_02_27_game_ai_module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_02_27_game_ai_module/</guid>
      <description>As part of the Game AI module I took at Goldsmiths University on February 2017 it was needed to design, implement and playtest an AI-based game. There was no technichal constraints or limitations. The idea was making something that could be useful later for my research and, as I need to use the GVGAI Framework, I opted to use it in order to get familiar with it. Valve&amp;rsquo;s Portal series are in the top of my favourite games list (check them out if you haven&amp;rsquo;t), so I decided to make my game based on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2017 - Her Resonance</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_01_23_global_game_jam_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_01_23_global_game_jam_2017/</guid>
      <description>The Global Game Jam (GGJ) is an annual game creation event taking place worldwide in different physical locations. At certain time, a theme is announced and jammers have 48 hours to make a game based on it. Thousands of people participate all around the world, creating thousands of games (more than 7000 games have been created in the 2017 edition) and the number increases every year.
IGGI signs up every year as one of the GGJ local sites, taking place in one of the collaborating institutions so, as part of the programme, I spent the weekend in York making a game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Development Module Project - Hungry Penguins Game</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2016_11_11_game_development_module/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2016_11_11_game_development_module/</guid>
      <description>At the IGGI Game Development Module I took at Goldsmiths University in November 2016, it was needed to develop a game using Unity. I teamed up with one of the other students of the programme, Rory Davidson, and we created a puzzle-platformer.
Game The idea of the game came up during the brainstorming session we had at the beginning of the module. We wanted to develop a game featuring penguins living in a city, being forced to steal fish in order to eat and survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello IGGI!</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2016_09_04_hello_iggi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2016_09_04_hello_iggi/</guid>
      <description>I am really excited to finally say Hello IGGI as I am one of the new students in the University of Essex! It is a great opportunity and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what comes out of the next 4 years!
But wait&amp;hellip; What is IGGI??  Right! I&amp;rsquo;ll explain!
The Intelligent Games and Game Intelligence (IGGI) PhD programme is the biggest fully funded research programme in Artificial Intelligence and Games in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>