<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/tags/entrepreneurship/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/tags/entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DEN Entrepreneurship Workshop 2017</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_09_19_DEN_entrepreneurship_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/post/2017_09_19_DEN_entrepreneurship_workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 19-20th September 2017, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://digitaleconomynetwork.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Digital Economy Network (DEN)&lt;/a&gt;, in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalcatapultcentre.org.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Digital Catapult&lt;/a&gt;, organised a two-days entrepreneurship workshop for EPSRC Digital Economy PhD students. As part of IGGI, I had the chance to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday I went to the Digital Catapult&amp;rsquo;s offices (where they have amazing views of St. Pancras!) with the idea of learning as much as possible from those two days, and I certainly did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive post_img_right&#34; src=&#34;http://kisenshi.github.io/img/posts/201709_DENworkshop/workshop_stpancras.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Starting up with St Pancras views&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philip Treleaven, professor at UCL, gave a series of lessons in entrepreneurship, including how to identify the idea, branding and vision, suggestions for the pitch and funding sources. These talks were really interesting as they provided a general overview of the steps to follow when you have an idea that you&amp;rsquo;d like to commercialize; or a way to put the researchs out there, converting what you are working, now or in the future, into a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also a series of talks given by former UCL students, who has succesfully started companies applying the knowledge they gained during their PhDs. They became with successfull companies like &lt;a href=&#34;http://predictionio.incubator.apache.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PredictionIO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://brainpool.ai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brainpool&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.satalia.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Satalia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://coinstrats.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CoinStrats&lt;/a&gt; and shared their stories with us. They provided an insight of what becoming an entrepreneur involves, including the issues they have found during their journeys and what they&amp;rsquo;ve learnt from the experience. They gave a series of really good advices in case we&amp;rsquo;d like to follow their steps in the future and I felt very inspired by them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop included a practical session where we had the chance to work with other attendees (PhD students from a range of different Universities) to identify a problem in the society and become with an idea to develop in order to solve it. We were divided into groups to work on a pitch to present the next day in front of the rest of the teams, and a panel, who would decide which team would win the Dragon&amp;rsquo;s DEN Pitching Competition, rewarded with £1000!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team, formed by Alex Owen (University of Southampton), Youssef Hamid (Loughborough University) and Yitong Huang (University of Nottingham), became with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CycleRack&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which won the competition! The idea was based in the existing problem of the lack of safe bike parking in big cities, which results in thousands of bikes stolen every year. Most of the people living in cities like London live in flats with no storage space, which difficult the storage of their bikes at home or makes it very inconvenient. For most cyclist, parking their bikes in the street at night or at certain times is not an option. The solution we came up with was creating a dynamic social bike parking app, which would take advantage of private&amp;rsquo;s spaces (people&amp;rsquo;s homes or businesses), as secure rental spaces to park other people&amp;rsquo;s bikes for a period of time. It&amp;rsquo;s based on the idea of AirBnB and these kind of &amp;lsquo;on the move&amp;rsquo; social apps that has been successful, applied to a concept that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been tried before. It took us some time to polish the idea and prepare the pitch, but it was really worth it as we were really happy with the final result and the presentation we did. I include a picture of the team when receiving the prize!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive post_img_center&#34; src=&#34;http://kisenshi.github.io/img/posts/201709_DENworkshop/cycleRack_team.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CycleRack team picture receiving the prize&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the big prize, there was also a People&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award, based on the choices of the rest of the teams, and rewarded with £250. The team of one of the colleagues in my program, Carlos Gonzalez Diaz (University of York), won this prize with their project &lt;em&gt;EmploAIble&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a really good experience, I enjoyed the workshop and met other students working in very interesting projects, which I think it is very important as well. Thank you to everyone who work to make it possible!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>