<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The_script on Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kispygr.github.io/tags/the_script/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The_script on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 08:35:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kispygr.github.io/tags/the_script/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Superheroes</title>
      <link>http://kispygr.github.io/post/2015_03_15_superheroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 08:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kispygr.github.io/post/2015_03_15_superheroes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night, The Script played in the O2 Arena for 17000 people and I was one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;post_img_right img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;http://kispygr.github.io/img/posts/concerts/the_script_painting_green.png&#34; alt=&#34;Paint the town green&#34;&gt;
The Irish band started the concert painting the Arena green and kept singing for one hour and a half going through most of their discography, encouraging the attendees to sing and jump with them to have a great Saturday night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They used as well a small stage in the middle of the stadium and, on his way back to the main one, Danny jumped into the stands, mic and GoPro in his hands, to be close to the fans and sing with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like this band as they have very motivational and inspiring songs (as &lt;em&gt;Hall of Fame&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Superheroes&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;It´s not right for you&lt;/em&gt;, my favourite!) and I had been waiting for the concert since I bought the tickets in October. It totally met my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They gave the fans all they wanted: music, lasers, tons of fun and a great performance of &lt;em&gt;Hall of Fame&lt;/em&gt; to close an amazing show. I can´t wait for future tours! In the meantime I would have to remember that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&#34;text-center&#34;&gt;You got one life, to love what you do!!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r6chhdfRQ44&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-responsive post_img&#34; src=&#34;http://kispygr.github.io/img/posts/concerts/the_script_finale.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Finale&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>