<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Cheese with posts</title>
    <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Cheese with posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>The content of this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kisenshi.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A little bit about me</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! I’m Cris; a Spaniard in love with London, where I’ve been living since 2013. Although I had always enjoyed creative tasks like drawing and painting; I opted for a more technical career, and I absolutely love it! I am passionate about solving problems, coding and the feel when something you have built actually works!
I worked as a web developer for a couple of years before I decided to make a change to the exciting world of AI and games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kisenshi.github.io/page/publications/</guid>
      <description>2021 Cristina Guerrero-Romero and Diego Perez-Liebana. &amp;ldquo;MAP-Elites to Generate a Team of Agents that Elicits Diverse Automated Gameplay&amp;rdquo;, Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG), 2021.
 
Related demo
 Diego Perez-Liebana, Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Alexander Dockhorn, Dominik Jeurissen and Linjie Xu. &amp;ldquo;Generating Diverse and Competitive Play-Styles for Strategy Games&amp;rdquo;. Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG), 2021.
 2020 Cristina Guerrero-Romero, Shringi Kumari, Diego Perez-Liebana and Sebastian Deterding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>